Your favorite movies are going to be destroyed.
Disaster Movie is a comedy, science fiction film directed by Jason Friedberg.
Over the course of one evening, an unsuspecting group of twenty-somethings find
themselves bombarded by a series of natural disasters and catastrophic events.
Will, played by Matt Lanter.
Amy, played by Vanessa Lachey.
Calvin, played by Gary 'G. Thang' Johnson.
Enchanted Princess / Amy Winehouse Look-A-Like / Jessica
Simpson Look-A-Like, played by Nicole Parker.
Juney / Hannah Montana, played by Crista Flanagan.
Lisa, played by Kim Kardashian.
Disaster Movie is a 2008 American parody film written and directed by Jason Friedberg
and Aaron Seltzer and produced by Peter Safran, Friedberg, and Seltzer.
It stars Matt Lanter, Vanessa Minnillo, Gary "G Thang" Johnson, Crista Flanagan, Nicole Parker, Ike
Barinholtz, Carmen Electra, Tony Cox, and Kim Kardashian in her feature film debut.
The film is mainly a parody of the disaster film genre, although it also references many
other films, television shows, people, and pop culture events of the time.
Initially intended as a parody of Superbad, directors Friedberg and Seltzer transitioned
the film as a satire of the disaster movie genre midway through production.
The directors also reportedly used trailer footage to get
an understanding of then upcoming films.
Filming took place from April to June 2008, with the title getting
revealed on the final day of the film's production.
The film was theatrically released by Lionsgate in the United States on August 29, 2008, and was universally panned by
critics and audiences, with many considering it to be the worst "movie" directed by Friedberg and Seltzer.
The film is often listed as one of the lowest-rated films of the
2000s, and one of the worst films of all time.
It was also a financial disappointment compared to Friedberg and Seltzer's
previous films, grossing $34.8 million on $20 million budget.
At the 29th Golden Raspberry Awards, the film received six nominations.
The film explores themes of transvestite, natural
disaster, parody, stupidity, spoof.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.